hey guys so we have this video of a
Pikachu Professor making a calculus
problem for their
students let's see if we can solve it
I'm pretty sure this is the equation
right here this is an integral from 2 Pi
to 10 of a whole bunch of trig stuff DX
if you want to try this on your own
pause it right now because I'm going to
solve it in three two one first let's
copy it down and let's give ourselves
some space I want to pull some stuff out
of this one right here on top I want to
pull out this cosine Cub 3x on bottom
the six and the eight have a two in
common so I want to pull that two out
which will turn the six into a three and
the eight into a four and let's also
pull a negative 1 out of both of these
so in the end we're factoring out a -2
now I'm ready to focus on this middle
piece right here let's clean it up a
little bit this looks very familiar to
me and the fact some of the inputs for
these are 3x I'm thinking we should
check the triple angle formulas I don't
have them memorized but I found them
here they are right here and this is
identical to this one right here so all
of this is equal to seeking of 3x and
secant means 1/ cosine so we can rewrite
this as 1/ cosine
3x now let's look at this cosine cubed
of 3x that Cube means that there are
three of them being multiplied by each
other and I'd like to take one of them
and put it over here and then for these
two let's recombine them into a cosine
squar now we have a cosine 3x over
cosine 3x they cancel to give us one and
then we're just multiplying by this one
so all of this can disappear and then
let's smush everything together right
now we're subtracting this second term
another way can think of it take the
subtraction symbol make the denominator
negative and add the two terms and now
both of our terms are being divided by
-2 that means they're both being
multiplied by - one2 so let's pull out
that - one2 and now we're just left with
cosine 2 3x+ sin^2 3x well this is a
Pythagorean identity sin s of theta plus
cosine sare thet is equal to 1 Theta can
be anything including 3x so sin s 3x +
cosine 3x is just going to be equal to 1
so using the Pythagorean identities we
just changed all of this stuff into one
and now we can smush everything together
and we're going to take this integral
the integral from 2 Pi to 10 of 1 that's
just going to be X evaluated from 2 Pi
to 10 and then we still have the - 1/2
in front so all this means is we're
going to take our - 1/2 and multiply it
by x - x where the first X is equal to
this top number 10 and this x is equal
to the bottom number 2 pi and now we're
ready to distribute the -22 * 10 is -5
and -2 * -2 piun is pi this is the
answer to Pikachu's challenge question
let's put a box around it how exciting